Guide to the James Buell Munn Collection 1873-1980 MC 2 MC.2
New York University Archives
- Series VI: Research Material, 237108
  - Physiologia Epicuro-Gassendo-Charltoniana, undated; 237157 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    General Note
    The origin of these photocopies is unknown.
- Addendum - Series I: Acquisition, 33540
  - Acquisition of Estate Collection/Munn Memorial Collection - Correspondence Includes correspondence, chronology describing the acquisition of the Munn Papers; Memorandum, c. Feb., 1977 by Jacob D. Goldstein detailing the history of the Estate Collection; "Major Achievements in the Archives Since Last Meeting of the Council," by Bayrd Still. Correspondents include Jacob D. Goldstein, Harley P. Holden, Hyman Lehon, Clifford H. Shipton, Bayrd Still. See also: Professor Still files for post-1978 correspondence., 1952-1978; 33547 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Contributions to Memorial Fund - Correspondence Material re receipt of funding needed to arrange the Estate Collection and develop the Memorial Collection. Correspondents include H. Thomas Austern, Jacob D. Goldstein, Jacob Rabkin, Bayrd Still., undated; 33546 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mailing Lists Includes lists of former students who contributed to fund for Mrs. Yerhage (Munn farm employee); former students who con­ tributed to Munn Scholarship Fund; students identified by B. Parnes as correspondents of Munn., undated; 33545 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Returned Letters Letters returned per "addressee Unknown.", undated; 33544 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Alumni/Colleagues - Correspondence Includes current correspondence with respect to the acqui­ sition of extant Munn papers and memoirs written by former students and colleagues at Washington Square College., 1978; 33543 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Munn Scholarship Fund - Correspondence Correspondence include Jill Claster, Bayrd Still., 1979; 33542 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Munn Students - Printed Material (about) Includes articles about: Jacob Goldstein Murray Israel Manfred E. Lee Alfred Marrow, undated; 33541 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Addendum - Series II: Munn Correspondence, 33538
  - Folders contain Munn correspondence received from: Melvin Albert - Nov., 1923 (copy; original in Estate Collection). H. Thomas Austern - Oct., 1927 - Nov., 1929. Alexander Baltzley - Yearly exchange of letters from Christmas 1936 to Christmas 1945; Dec. 1948 - Dec., 1957 (intermittent); Mrs. Munn, February, 1960; December, 1928, Francis J. Bloustein, 1925-1942, Benjamin and Dorothy Butner - Oct. - Nov. 1932; Nov. - Dec. 1933. Julius Evans - 1932; 1947-1948 Jacob D. Goldstein - May, 1926 Isidore S. Immerman - Jan.-Feb., 1924; June, 1926; Jan., 1947; April - May, 1959; Jan. 1962; March 1968; March, 1972; Feb., 1973; June, 1974. (Includes correspondence from Mrs. Munn). Sidney Leibowitz - Sept., 1931 - June, 1935. James L. Mandel - Aug., 1947; Nov., - Dec., 1962; March, 1960s Jacob Rabkin - Nov., 1949; July, 1951; Nov., 1952. Arthur I. Singer - July, 1943 - Nov., 1945 Hyman Lehan - Dec. 27, 1956 Irving H. Jurow - June - July, 1926; May 1971 - June 1974 Charles Norman - Aug. 1968 - Aug. 1971, 1923-1971; 33539 (Box 10)
- Addendum - Series III: Memoirs, 33536
  - Folders contain memoirs of Munn received from H. Thomas Austern - July, 1979. (Includes memorandum by B. Parnes re meeting between H.T. Austern Bayrd Still, Alexander Baltzly - Jan. 1976. Written at request of William L. Blackwell, Chairman, History Department). Margaret L. Brown - April 20, 1979 (Bayrd Still oral history interview). Benjamin Butner - see Sept 15, 1979 letter to Bayrd Still. Series I, Folder 5. Rabbi Armond E. Cohen - Jan. 25, 1982 letter to Dean Jill N. Claster, WSUC Miguel A. de Capriles - May, 1976 (Excerpts, Bayrd Still oral history interview). Jacob Fisher - 1978 (See also: Jacob Fisher, On Vanishing Ground, 1979, NYU Archives, Rz 1). John Frost - Bulletin (of NYU Libraries); article, 1964; letter, 1979. Isidore S. Immerman - Sept. 13, 1979 (Transcript of discussion with Bayrd Still). Sidney Leibowitz - June, 1979. James L. Mandel - Sept. 2, 1979 (Includes list of letters from Mandell to Munn Located in Munn Collection, Harvard University Library). Bernard Newman - Sept 14, 1979 Teresa Newman - Sept. 5, 1979 Charles Norman - See: Charles Norman, The Well of the Past, 1949. NYU Archives, Rz 2; Poets and People, 1972, NYU Archives, Rz 3. Leon Pomerance - Sept. 1, 1979 George Saslow - July, 1979 Hilda G. Schwartz - Sept. 20, 1979 William R. Taylor - May 27, 1980., 1976-1982; 33537 (Box 10)
- Addendum - Series IV: Photographs, 33534
  - H. Thomas Austern - photograph of John P. and James B. Munn "receiving the Colors" at New York University, c. 1920's; Munn in 1963. Isidore Immerman - Alpha Lambda Phi dinner meeting, May 28, 1927. (see oversized box) Mrs. Bruno Lever - photograph of JBM in Washington Square College Yearbook Album, n.d., ca.1920-1963; 33535 (Box 11)
- Addendum - Series V: Publications - Munn Students, 33532
  - Murray Israel - Offprints of professional articles Charles Norman - The Well of the Past (1949).- Poets and People (1979)., 1949, 1979; 33533 (Box 11)
- Addendum - Series VI: Material derived from New York University Archives, 33528
  - Munn correspondence - New York University Administration, 1926-1932; 33531 (Box 11)
  - Photographs - Dr. J.P. Munn, Chancellor Brown, Major Marilsky on viewing Stand; November 23, 1917. See also: New York University Archives Photograph Collection Commencements, 33530 (Box 11)
  - Military, undated; 33529 (Box 11)
- Addendum - Series VII: James Buell Munn Exhibit (May - September, 1980), 33523
  - Correspondence and publicity (see Bayrd Still files) Brochure, 1980; 33527 (Box 11)
  - Photographs by Paul Occhiogrosso, 1980; 33526 (Box 11)
  - Labels/Inclusions (for use in Archives exhibit case), 1980; 33525 (Box 11)
  - Munn Exhibition Brochures, 1980; 33524 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Unprocessed Accession 10.014 (Box 13)
- Oversized Photographs (Box 14)
  General
  Originally labeled box 12. Material from both Series V and VI